This is Hacker Public Radio Episode 4,111 from Monday to 6 May 2024.
Today's show is entitled, HPR Community News for April 2024.
It is part of the series HPR Community News.
It is hosted by HPR volunteers and is about 70 minutes long.
It carries an explicit flag.
The summary is, HPR volunteers talk about shows released and comments posted in April 2024.
Hi everybody, my name is Ten Falon and you're listening to another exciting episode
of Hacker Public Radio today.
It is the HPR Community News for April 2024.
And joining me this evening is, hello Dave Morris, hi Dave, how are you?
I'm good, I'm good, thank you very much and we're recording on a slightly unusual date
and time but that's all to the good places.
You show us how flexible we are.
Yeah, places too for a race.
Yeah, so some family commitments that I need to take care of, it's been a hectic month.
It doesn't look like it's going to stop in a hectic month, I need time soon.
So we will continue to persevere.
If there's one thing that HPR does is continue to plot on.
HPR is a community podcast network and that means podcasts are crowdsourced from the community.
Who is community?
The people listening to this show, you are the community.
And we are the janitors.
What are janitors, Dave, in the context of HPR?
You keep asking me this question.
Well, where the guy is?
At the moment we're guys, yes, we haven't really recruited any non-guide people.
And we look after the sort of infrastructure, the metadata, the background.
In fact, we have virtual mobs and buckets and a flow to mop, I think.
And there are plenty of mobs available folks in all Conner shades,
sizes of the rainbow.
And feel free to bring your own mop.
If there's stuff on HPR that you think you can contribute to the community,
it ain't an ivory tower.
You don't need to build an application form.
You just need to do equally, submitting shows.
After a quite good burst, the beginning of the year,
we're reasonable amount in the reserve queue, but we are seeing a slow down again
in the amount of contributions.
This is typical for this time of year, but if you haven't contributed to the show,
please do so.
There are free slots coming up.
We will be posting reserves shows.
So keep the community alive.
Keep the project alive by submission shows.
And this show is where we review the news and the stuff that's been happening.
And the most important thing is where we welcome new host, Dave,
and that is traditionally something that you do.
It certainly is.
I'm not quite sure why, but there we go.
I'm very happy to do it.
And this month we have a new host,
new in one respect, Dave Hingley.
And Dave is the brother of Mike Hingley, who's an existing host.
And I think if we've been to Ocamp,
we will admit both of these brothers at the very point.
Dave has helped us join us and is wonderful to see him.
I was absolutely chuffed to see that show coming in.
Absolutely chuffed.
Yes.
So the Hingley brothers are indeed very close to what I consider the HPR community.
So good grace to have them officially on board as these.
As hosts, nothing else.
So things, other things.
Okay, Annie, who during this show, the community news,
well, we do Dave and I put down our proverbial mobs and hypothetical mobs.
And we come out of the closet so speak.
And we go through all the shows that have been aired in the last month,
and give you a little bit of a summary.
In case you haven't downloaded them yourself or you're just following the feed for this particular show.
But you know to go back and get these episodes.
And as sometimes happens episode four or a six was the community news for March 2024.
And there were two comments on that show.
I won't repeat.
Okay, you do yours.
I had a senior moment on that recording.
So as my excuse, anyway.
And I used the word diatribe in appropriately.
And so I apologize to Scotty because it was his show.
I was talking about and commenting on his show.
Let me read it.
Apologies Scotty.
In commenting on show four or eight through a called a diatribe,
which means a rant or critic writing.
I think I was probably going for discussion or discourse or similar.
It wasn't a diatribe, I think.
I mean, the face of library where sometimes don't pop into my mind when call for or the wrong one does.
So thanks again for bringing in out of the time.
And that's my excuse and I'm sticking with it.
I thought it was a good excuse.
What do you mean?
Some guy on the internet replied.
Two Dave Morris.
Dear Dave.
No worries.
I am known for panic written pro.
Latching nonsense.
Hopefully your show will encourage more men to discuss men's health.
Thank you.
Yes.
Good show.
So the next one was getting started with a
DiddyCam photo management software.
And unbelievably,
this by Henrik, there are no comments on this.
DiddyCam is such a fantastic piece of software.
Yeah, I used it for a number of years.
But I think I loaded loads of pictures into it at one point years ago.
And just sort of left in there.
I don't take pictures much these days.
So it was really interesting to hear about it.
Because there's changed a lot since I last used it.
And so it really attempted me to go back and do some stuff with it.
Organize things better.
Because it's all about editing stuff and changing stuff.
And organizing really the thing that I wanted it for.
Can I find that picture of such and such?
Absolutely.
Yes.
Because it's in that collection or it's searchable or whatever.
So yeah.
Excellent show.
Really good.
It's on my list.
And this is the second on what I hope will be a series.
So good stuff.
Keep in common.
Yeah.
And folks, you can contribute to HVR by giving you the post and the comments.
Give a little bit a little bit of positive feedback really helps.
Sometimes on the internet,
I learned more bash tips.
And there's no comments on this on either.
But that's not going to stop us from commenting do.
Indeed not.
No, it's some some nice couple of scripts which are which are listed here.
And explained in a lot of detail in the show which I think is a great thing.
It's really nice to have more contributions to the bash scripting series,
which goes away way back to the early days of HVR.
So yeah.
Yeah.
I was going to comment on this.
But I think I actually message Scotty himself because there was an issue with his notes.
And said,
You want me to do this to your notes to fix them.
And by the way, the show was really good.
So I should make sure that I got it.
I should be more public in my chat chat.
So yeah.
So I did find this to be very good.
We definitely need more of this sort of stuff I'd say.
And I tend to have comments on my head,
which I sort of reserve for commenting on this show.
What I probably should just type them in.
But then if there's a day where I forget to do that,
people might feel like I have them to do their show when I want to.
And some of this is not available.
Yeah.
I usually do what you said.
I think as listening,
I'm sort of constructing a comment in my head.
And then I forget.
Because things constructed in my head tend to fall out fairly quickly.
So yeah.
But yeah.
Oh, and he's this show is actually in two series.
Although we can't do that.
But.
Yeah.
I learned the best scripting series,
which I find quite amusing.
Yeah.
We'll be good.
We can use that one as a.
And this is an example when we do get to the point of fixing that issue.
Oh.
Um.
Modifying Python scripts with some help from chess.
GPT.
This is from Mr. X.
And he is using the.
Um.
HBR.
Modifying your Python code to.
Or without some chat.
GPT.
What do you think?
Excellent.
I've done the same.
I actually commented to him in person.
But forgot.
It's too right.
Anything on the show itself.
I think I'm going to lose my Janice's badge if I keep this up.
But um.
Yeah.
I like what he did here.
It.
It was an interesting way.
Oh, and necessary way.
I feel I don't.
I think he could solve this easily.
But he just he also wanted to use it as a way of finding out how useful chat
GPT is in.
Exactly.
To solve these sorts of problems.
And that is that is excellent.
Yeah.
And he got there.
And do you know what?
He also made me think.
Hmm.
We need a series of shows about how your process Jason files in.
We do indeed.
Yes.
It's back to my get round for that one day.
And I've made a series that I'm going to contribute to.
That's I'm living for a few years ago.
It's living in XML now.
I'm living in Jason.
Yep.
Yeah.
It's interesting subject.
To go to me.
There's a few episodes on that spoiler alert.
No comments on this one either, which is playing civilization part three part one.
And after doing this by a whole go of course who else.
Commissioner strategy James and we had already civilization and civilization part two.
And now we're on civilization part three part one.
That makes sense to me at least.
Yes.
You have to differentiate between Roman numerals and the Arabic ones.
Exactly.
It's interesting what they do to make games more interesting over time.
It's particularly strategy ones.
I find it interesting more the talking about the game and the programming.
The idea behind that a hookah has given us the stories in the developers mind about what's going on and how they're.
Adam improvements and stuff.
So it's a great insight not only into how to play the game but the thoughts behind developing a game.
So great.
Great shows there.
Sort of high level view of the concept of games like this is quite interesting.
Cool.
Now we had noticed with a test driven development demo.
And this I found was super super useful for me.
This clearly explained the concept.
And we'll be used as a reference.
Absolutely guaranteed internally here.
And for explained to people.
What it is.
What is it?
For experiments people what it is and how you use it.
Yep.
It.
Yeah.
I found it most intriguing.
I've not really spent any brain power on.
I'm putting up more about it.
So it was very good to hear this.
I've been as I've been coding myself.
I write quite a lot of bash scripts for stuff.
And I find myself.
When I was listening to this go on.
I don't know if I would ever do test driven development.
And then as I was doing it, I was realizing everything that I'm doing within my script.
I'm checking for this file.
Does this file exist?
Yes.
I'm checking for this.
So we like trivial as I'm writing it to write the equivalent test driven scenario.
Pull it out of my code.
You know, they've statement.
If this file exists and does not empty then,
then you could have an assertion on in the test file.
Go on assert that this file exists.
And so as you're developing, you can equally be doing the test driven.
So, yep.
I don't know if that is a thing.
But more thought, more thought required by me.
And it's a great episode because it has me thinking about the whole thing.
Not necessarily, but I will do it or agree with it.
Well, I'm definitely thinking about is as a development model.
Yeah, it's a different mindset.
And it's quite interesting to hear if only for that reason,
to make you rethink things you do.
When I was, when I became a, again, paid for that,
I was going to say a professional program.
That's a bit behind-the-loop.
When I got paid for doing programming,
I picked up a method which was very much all the rage in the 1970s
called step-wise refinement.
Where you wrote a program which said, you know, being an end,
and nothing in the middle.
And then you put some comments in there and said,
this point I'm going to do this, then I'm going to do that,
then I'm going to do that.
And you went to each comment and expanded it,
which this was the refinement.
So you wrote out all the steps.
And sometimes you saw some sub steps that you needed to add in.
And then you went and refined them by expanding them.
But it was, I don't know.
It was Glasgow computer science that originated from, I think,
but I'm not sure.
And it was in Pascal, because Pascal was the language that I used
on on deck, back to the MS, because that was their favourite language
at the time.
That's the one that got the most support.
So that worked great for me.
I suppose I sort of semi-do that now, but not formally.
So it's this methodology is quite interesting,
and you know, making you think in different ways
or in organized ways.
So yeah, true.
And now for something completely different.
Following day, we had more man talk,
but some guy on the internet talks about B days and other things.
And there.
Yeah, yes.
There are two comments.
I'll read four keys one.
Oh, no.
I really wished I had more ideas for shows.
So I could help press down this kind of show
from some guy on the internet to the reserve queue smiley face.
And.
That's nice.
I like that.
Yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
I think he said.
Yeah.
So we are ignating on the concept somewhere.
Yes.
Second comment is from Mad Sweeney,
squeezing out his show.
He says,
I think I feel the show building up inside.
If only I could flush it out.
I could do.
It's very good.
And some.
I kept hearing B day,
which is I think the French pronunciation
pronounces B day,
and I kept going,
did you say,
is that you're straight?
Is that Australian?
In my.
Because I.
Yeah, exactly.
Australians are fair bit,
but we don't know how B day got turned into that.
We do the same.
We're done.
Yeah.
But.
It.
My daughter.
Was watching some show on YouTube,
which was about somebody
fitting one of these things.
And we're worried about whether he could fit it on his toilet
when he was in an apartment rented apartment.
And nobody seemed to be all that bothered.
But yeah, it's just a sort of fairly shallow thing
with a cold water supply.
So yeah,
the chilly day,
that's going to be.
Quite.
Yeah.
chilly.
Good tips there on.
Going.
post-market OS will give you loads of options for what OS to install, but I don't know which one.
I don't know what desktop environment is, so if somebody has a tip for me that would be great,
I would appreciate it. Yeah, cool. It was nice and detailed. Yeah, excellent stuff.
So the next day we had Daniel with one year of Linux in which he, the experiences of running Linux full-time for a year.
Very simple. There are three comments, and I'll do the first, which was R&B. Boxing Linux.
I've never had any problems with Linux until Ubuntu 23.10, waiting for 24.04 LTS.
Focus it. Thank you. Thank you for your show. Interesting to hear from someone coming from Windows to Linux with an open mind.
Being on Linux since 2001 and only using Windows when constrained to it by a university or employer,
it's always good to get the view of the other side. Absolutely.
Hendrik, uh, responded saying, enjoyable to learn about Linux use a case and experience.
It was an enjoyable listen to your Linux experience. I went over to Linux as my daily driver in December
2023, Linux Mint, Debian edition, and MDE. We have different use cases, but nevertheless,
interesting to learn some about your needs and experience. Great stuff. Yeah, excellent.
It was an interesting show. It's good to hear that sort of viewpoint in a balanced way,
is it? Yeah, absolutely. And yeah, so we're panicking for doing that.
And the following day, we had Delta Ray, uh, 27 years of Linux, which rumbles on for 45 minutes,
and overexagging this overexaggerates about how awesome it is to use Linux.
And essentially, what he does is go through every app that he has installed. And this is
very, very close to the what I'm running instead of an XFCE, I'm running LXD. And what it
is essentially a complete list of all the stuff that I currently have on my machine as well.
So I'm very happy to see that. Probably because I follow him on MasterDone,
stuff, and I have installed and Twitter, and I have installed some utilities from Command 9.net.
So yeah, there we go. Three comes. Excellent show. It was my feeling too. It's yeah, I think he
beats me in terms of years of Linux. I can't get to 27. I can't remember when I started to
work lately, but so yeah, excellent. I think I'm 23. Yeah, I think I'm probably in the, I can't
remember that clearly. I know it was some red hat when it was a desktop thing. But yeah, uh,
so I was running that on a cast off PC that we could get from work because they clear that
the student labs, you could, you could ask for one, and you got a load, a crappy old PC.
Yeah, it was right. Well, I've had, sorry, I was I installed an X more than 25, maybe 27 years
ago, yeah. But, um, running is a modular driver. It will be 1890 years, 1890 years. Okay,
anyway, there we go. I had a cool. Anyone's welcome? I mean, that's the thing. No, no, no,
of course it's, it's good to hear these, these stories from long since. So come in from Nick
correction. Hi, great podcast. Thank you. Small correction. The Oracle virtual box extensions are
not fast, but they're free for personal use. And Delta RSS, thanks, you're right, Nick,
thanks. What I failed to mention during the podcast is that while it is indeed free for
personal use, it's not available to make personal use claims anymore because I needed
that user's work and Oracle detects this and sends a nasty gram to the organization asking them to
pay. Wow. That's Oracle. Yep. Henry Cameron says, interesting review of your Linux softwares.
I like to show your review of your softwares include several I use. Some have not heard of,
but have interest and some I know, but not started to use and some not in my current need.
One of those I've installed and started to look at is Gramps. And I was happy to hear your
positive comment about it, which gives me more confidence to use it. When you talked about your
early Linux days, it was when I used some workstation with their Unix as my daily job driver.
I believe I started with son in the 1990s, had it for probably more than a decade of job.
I liked the Unix environment. And I remember a colleague talked about Linux when I was very new,
and that became interested in Linux, but it was much later I actually started to use Linux.
I could relate to several details in your story to my Unix background. Finally, you mentioned
the freedom to put the operating system and other software I want to on my device. One big device,
many have is a car, and I believe modern cars lack software freedom. Anyone with knowledge
in modern cars software is please enlighten us in a pod show. Yes, very nice. That will be interesting,
indeed. Yeah, I know nothing about that at all. It would be fascinating to be able to hack
a rubbish software that you often find on cars, like I was over 10 years old. So let's
really expect the software to be rubbish, but like you can't turn the radio off. It's impossible
to turn the radio. What you do is you press the turn off and it just goes very quiet. And then
it gradually creeps back up again. So you get the sound of the radio coming on when you
start the car late at very low level. And I took that, I asked engineer at garage. He said,
oh, yeah, they're all doing that. I think it's all the same software in all of them. So they all do that.
Yeah, yeah. So you know, probably a bit of a show of go away. Unbelievable.
So yeah, good show. Good show. Good show. Good show. Good show. It's very good. Oh,
Gramps. So it's going to comment about Gramps. Not nothing anybody's ever talked about on
age. Where are that I recall? I used to use it. I somehow stopped using it because I ran out of
real motivation to do it. No, no, no. There's still lots, there's loads of lurking in
censuses from ancient times. I found one who was on a ship band for the bore wall, which
believed in a census like, and on my grandmother's brothers. Anyway, yeah, Gramps has moved on enormously,
such that I can't take my XML version of my database and turn it into Gramps anymore. That's a
project I really, really want to pick up on. It's like, you know, have to hand craft the XML and
stick it into the, you know, hand read it and put it back into a Gramps filter. Yeah, it's
I'm about at least when I've stored a lot of information in there with the view that
well, my, or my father was alive. I focused more on getting information out of him whenever
whenever I was home visiting, I would take the time to ask him about that. So now I have all this
information, but, you know, it's not cross reference, there's not check, there's not whatever,
so if there are people who have used Gramps, please do some shows on us because it would be, yeah,
it would be very useful for for me, essentially. And me. Okay. Yeah, yeah, that would, that would be
super. Right. Next. The next one was power of twos and, well, did you have the same thing
Dave, when you were processing the show going, is this spam? I did. And I was, how the hell is it
going to get later? Because it was sent in as a piece of plane text. And of course HTML would have
just turned into one, but gigantic number. We'd probably with spaces in it or something, but yeah,
yeah. But, and for the view, not looking at the show notes, it's basically the show notes are
two new line, four new line, eight new line, 16 new line, 32. Yeah, and that continues on for a lot of
lines. Yeah, yeah, it's really good. Yes. Who's trying to do my, and that's, I'll do those two,
and you can do your own research. Okay. Okay. Okay. When the goal says, very enjoyable episode,
I can't wait to find out what happens in the sequel. Each viewer is one, nine, two, and I was
going, huh? And then I realized, uh, this is for oh, nine, six, everybody. Yes. It takes a special
brain when you go to be able to figure that one out. Thank you very much. Right. And now,
I also says another example, one of the powers of two is mentioned in Enders game, Enders
runs through the powers of two to claim to count themselves down an early way of counting
10 enjoyable. It is lovely, I like that. No, I used to suffer from insomnia when I was younger,
and I used to do powers of two in my head to show or try to, I'm not very far, but that was one
way of trying to sleep. Anyway, I commented, and I comment, uh, title is eight, three, eight, six,
seven. Great show, thanks. It got me looking at slash, et cetera, slash services to remind
myself about, in a signed, important, because that was, I think he was talking about, um, and then
back in the 1970s when I abandoned my biology PhD and got a job instead, I ended up working in
the computer service department at Lancaster University in the Northwest of England, where we had
an ICL 1900 series mainframe. This is a 24-bit machine, which is Magnet Call Memory, which you believe,
running an operating system called George III. It's when I'll break this up with nice cuddly names.
When somebody left, I stumbled into working and there's a assembly language program using the plan
assembly on an ICL-200, or 1900, because we had a source access to the operating system,
which was on micro-fish, which you never want to do, if you can help. And we're enhancing it with
other universities in the region to implement an early form of networking, and that we're called GANET.
But into my memory from that day to this is the value of two to the 24-1, which is eight,
three, double eight, six, so seven. Of course, it's the largest signed integer that can be stored
in 24 bits, slightly face. Oh, and because I was looking at the HPI database today, I feel I am
in the presence of greatness, because not only is the show number 4096, the duration in seconds
is 102-4. Wow, that was a hundred percent look. It's not wonderful, yeah. But I think that's
his original length, because we store that as opposed to adding the infrastructure, yeah, so maybe you
do the surface. He is crafted this specifically. So this is what I say, the presence of greatness
definitely. That takes some detail to achieve that. I wonder of how many other little
easter eggs there are in the show. Yeah, absolutely amazing. I didn't enjoy that. I don't know why
it was just a nice episode that really for me, it's the sort of thing that HDR throws off now
again. Just you have no idea, just I love the episode. It's great, great work. Following day,
we'll take our jobs. Of course, they will. A bladder on about thoughts on robots taking our jobs
about do the dummy. And this was an interesting one, actually. And there are two comments.
One thing that do the dummy, oh sorry. I was trying to get where we were as your turn, yeah,
you had a big spielder. Do the dummy. The next thing, the one thing I forgot to mention in the previous
was when tech obsolete, there have been new things for the people to do or make. I'm not seeing
the new things in this case. And he also says, I know that people still smart people saying,
hey, I will not take your jobs, but have you seen the latest at the very least taking heads,
should be worried. Talking heads should be worried. On the other hand, the people who rise to talking
heads maybe just don't need the talking head part now. Here's a video demo. There's a link
in there showing an example of AI taking our jobs. But it was interesting from the point of view that
you know, that's what computing has been doing since, you know, day one. And the
computers are going to take our jobs. I remember, like my father lost his job as a result of
being computerized. And the jobs replacing the jobs are, yes, there are jobs to replace
the jobs, but it's usually an order of magnitude fewer jobs, maybe higher value, but fewer jobs.
So there you go. And I, he met the point about how many people he may have met on the
point, by improving scripting and stuff. And I was thinking, gosh, I don't quite a bit of that myself
in order. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Me too. Me too. Yeah. Yeah. The only comment I made to myself on this
one, I'm terrible at writing comments to people. I'm sorry. Was that, yeah, I don't disagree at all,
but, but a number of people won't. What you just said, that the number of jobs were diminished.
But what, that's point at which we need UBR universal basic income to, because that's always
been the vision of the future. You know, robots will do things and we'll have less less demand on us,
which will be a good thing. So long as we get in, because, you know, as things start at the moment,
here we are, we're just having a socialist communist point of view. Yeah. This is common sense.
Common sense. Yeah. Do you want to be a socialist opinion, Dave? It's my common sense. Okay.
Anyway. I mean, that's my name. I'm not disagree with you, but that's my political opinion.
However, yeah, though, it is, it is interesting. I feel like this the first time that the IT industry
have the, gosh, this computer is taking our jobs might actually affect us and we're scared.
Yeah. Yeah. It's true. Mm-hmm. Yes. It's definitely going to make a massive difference.
It also thinks, but yeah, it's, it's, yeah, I can't predict it.
I'm, one part to me says, yeah, well, if you're such a bad programmer person, like,
where the day I can do your job, then, you know, you shouldn't be doing that job. And then,
on the other hand, I'm thinking, yeah, but that call will not be met by that person. That call will be
met by that person's HR department. So whether they are, they are not. It'll still be met.
The cost, the cost savings and their cost will be met. And then they, in hernt mess, that's left as a result,
will be left behind. So yeah. Yeah. That was my political opinion. Those opinions are mine and
not that it just really goes a factor of radio. Just stand and back. This is a great thing to have
a show like that also thrown into the mix where, you know, you're kind of forced to think really
about actions and reactions and stuff. And, you know, when we looked at the coopers who lost all their
jobs because aluminium barrels came and we kind of went, oh, I don't make barrels, so I don't care.
Oh, sure. Sure. It's my son's working in the area of a herbs that I've said many times.
And his position exists because all the local banks probably all the banks in the entire UK have
reduced the number of actual physical banks enormously. So the times when used to go and ask for advice
about this, that the other local branch, just down the road, of all gone. And you're supposed to
phone up some chatbot and have a chat with them with that, with it. So it's there. It's
clear as clear as day. But I don't have, I'm glad that DODD dummy did this because I think he's got
a clearer view. And I have, I tend to get lost in the weeds very quickly thinking about this. And so
it's good to have his view point on it. I think it's early days with the AI that we have at the moment.
It's predictive, very good predictive text pretending to be, as somebody says, it's a, it's a
power pretending to speak. But yeah, we'll see. We will see, following day, road trips without GPS,
a short off the cuff discussion about how we navigate it, road trips in the past. And this is by
tree. And I mean, you might, uh, great tips, basically. Great, uh, and there was one comment.
Yes, my archer 72 says road trips without GPS. This is an interesting show and I'm looking
at the transcription to see what I'm missing. I recently found myself also losing signal.
I've got it back by cycling in and out of airplane mode to remedy the problem.
Just to get me thinking that I should also have a backup as I travel semi frequently from
Kentucky to the Chicago area suburbs, also because of my family situation, depending on which location
I travel, it's between 350 and 400 miles. With this last road trip and also some roads that I
wanted to avoid, I had to using OSA OSM and, as I said, OSM and, which causes, which uses
open strict map in the background, I would have to read the transcript to catch all your points,
which were very interesting. I'll probably be getting at least a handheld CB radio in the near future.
Also, it's been 20 years or so, but I used to print out directions from map quest
if the destination was somewhat local. Thanks for your show.
Yeah, I bought to, I was thinking when I was listening to this, I was in the position where
one done in New Year's Eve to collect my daughter from a party somewhere and, on the way back,
it kept the navigation systems kept rerouting me over a furry on the Rhine, which A pulls that
tended to lock in the night. Every single road was there, so I ended up having to drive to Rotterdam,
which is completely out of the way, and then from there, following the regular boring road signs
up. Thankfully, I have the maps for this as a backup. Thankfully, OSM Android now has the ability to
allow you to go back via a specific direction, so you can follow if you do a route down,
and you do route tracking, you can track that route back, so you can go back the same way,
which is actually nice. Oh, yeah, that's really nice. Yeah, yeah, yeah. I had a job as a van driver at one point,
just to supplement my student level. I heard about all your jobs.
Yeah, it was a part-time job as I was doing my advanced degree thingy, and yeah, and that was
way before GPS. So I got quite good at storing, that was driving around Manchester and the
environment, so sort of Lancashire area. I got a pretty good at working out routes myself,
but there were times when you'd come off a motorway, and then I went to a roundabout,
and then, oh, God, which one of my, which of these are these nine exits I'd take. So I evolved
the method going round around about several times to read all the exits, and then, oh, it was number
three. Oh, I think it was, you know, because I don't know if anybody spotted that,
thought I was insane maybe, but it was a way of just sort of taking stock and also finding
labels and looking at that with a common thing to do doing that sort of stuff. But yeah, I got
pretty good at it. And for our American listeners, a roundabout is a circular four-way stop sign.
Traffic circle, the time that traffic circle. They tend to use some, some cities have got lots of
maybe that also. They're not, they're not popular. When I took my kids to America to do
your semity in various places around California, I sat for nights looking on Google Maps,
and working at all the routes, and then I printed them out, so we had a sheet for this stuff.
Even though we hired a car with GPS, it didn't work. It didn't seem to get, it didn't charge
from the car for some reason or that. So you'd start off and then the thing would die,
you'd charge it in the hotel, and then it would last, you know, for a while. We kept turning it off all the time.
So we actually used these maps for a bit. What was that? What was the name of the company? I can't
remember who we hired from, but they were Alamo, that's right, Alamo. They said, oh yeah, yeah,
we don't, we don't relate to power stuff of our, of our USBs in the cars. So how are we supposed to
use this GPS? I don't know, I just work here. Yeah, tell me me. Yeah, but yeah, that's enough
anecdotes, I think, but yeah, it's a fascinating subject. It's the archer 72 comments about
getting map quests, maps, and stuff back in the day is also my experience in the UK version.
Always good to have a backup or a record. Okay, following day, an introduction to Home Assistant
and new series, all about Home Automation, this time, an introduction to Home Assistant, where I,
more or less read other people's websites, and what better method is, exactly.
Henrik says, looking forward to learn more about Home Assistant, I'm uncertain if, when or to what
extent I start with Home Automation. Although it can be fun, I only wanted in the case where this
better to our add value also for a not-convict device. Anyway, I have been looking at Home
Assistant, which would be my first school for Home Automation, so I'm looking forward to learn
more about it here on the hacker public radio. And I'm looking forward to having the time to do this.
Yes, yes. I also, as I, you know, because I've told you, I'm planning Home Assistant at some point,
but not getting on with it very fast at the moment, but yeah, yeah, that would be nice.
But I'm not, I think, probably have the same view as Henrik, I don't really want to
have cameras at my door and chat in with the guide delivering to the wrong house and stuff.
But yeah, something that opens and shuts the blinds would be nice. There's something, yes.
There's, and that's what I hope to be able to do build a foundation on this, but installing
Home Assistant at least as a base. And then, then some sample use cases of, like, just tell
the temperature or whatever, whatever we come across, see what's useful, and then people can build
upon that and refer to these shows, which are the foundations, to get them into the,
uh, into the, up to speak, basically. And hopefully, uh, two shows, but they're, they're an
experience. Exactly. Exactly. Exactly. Yep. Yep. Charles Town, South Carolina,
we've visited South Carolina when we meet up with some friends. This is a show from Hooka,
who was traveling this early roundabout, South Carolina. As a little while ago now,
calls his retired, as retired from the town, and traveling with me in Charleston, South Carolina.
And I do apologize to everybody going, Ken, that is not a South Carolina accent. I appreciate that.
Well, so, have you heard any of the Irish accents on American TV lately? It might defense
if it's just sweet and white. It's Charleston, by the way. Well, they're also known as in the dance,
you know, that's tough. Yeah. Very good. No. Again, they, uh, look at the photos and read
their signs, et cetera. Yeah, yeah, I had a, had a most enjoyable half hour, so hunting through all this
stuff, um, after listening to what even while listening to the show, yeah, very good.
AIOMG, some other guy on the internet talks about artificial intelligence, and this is operator.
And, uh, yeah, um, operator is operating as a completely different level to me, uh, with this AI
agents. This all makes, I was following this, as it was listening to it. But now for the life of
me, I have no clue. Um, I just found it very, now I'm looking at a very confusing photo,
Dave, your thoughts. Well, I had this in Louisville, so I wrote down, uh, here that I had, I missed about
90% of it. But, uh, there feels, it feels like there's a lot of really important information,
very valuable stuff in there. But, uh, until I know more, I need more context to,
to be able to, to dig into it more. Um, so I'm hoping that gradually I will learn more about this than
be able to say, oh, it was a show about this. I can go and check some, check some stuff in there to find
so yeah, it, it, it's, yeah, I'm pretty much on the same level as you. Yeah, but obviously he is using
it, uh, for stuff that, um, I'm not. So, not fantastic. Yeah, massive notes. This is really, really,
I applaud him at work. It's gone into this. Okay, the next day was archer 72 with more MPV
quick tips. And this was the, uh, text to speech version, which I was listening to and I really
had to go to the transcript to go, what is, what is he saying? I'm not sure the tips really,
you're reading out all go slash dot zero zero zero zero. Was, was the best use of a text to
know, no, no, that, those zeros really go. It's, it's quite hard to understand the, uh, the, the full context
that the full details of the show because I, my brain gets stuck totally on the, the numbers.
I just, I just, they saw a rattle about in my head where I should be listening to the, the next
bit and I can't because I'm stuck on those weird, weird chains of numbers, which I'm trying
to somehow to make sense of. And they're not really that important. No, yeah. Well, uh, the point
was he had his, um, history for MPV and bookmarks and stuff like that. So it was reading that out
and there was a lot of, um, a lot of stuff like URL links and stuff, uh, data codes and play
times, which, uh, if you were reading it, you were probably skip over, you know, the links,
just read it. Yeah, exactly the title of the, of the, of the link, and then leave the,
the listener to, uh, and things that I'm saying, you shouldn't send in the text to speech show.
It's just, uh, if you're sending in text to speech show, uh, try and have just text and not
computer output. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. How far, arches of new do doesn't, doesn't get
annoyed at me now for saying that. I think the, the concept of it was, was great, but, uh, yeah, the,
especially, I, which take the time and the ass has arches of new dooms up to turn, uh,
turn my links into into proper links, not reveal their, their weirdness, you know, with all the
commas and percent some things in it, um, because it's, it's better for the, for the ice, it's
better for understanding. Yeah. So, but, of course, GTA S ain't going to do that. It's going to
borrow, borrow, right in, I guess. But, uh, I'm wondering how you got the bookmarks like that, um,
yes, I've never, uh, I use MPV all the time. It's brilliant. Uh, we use the main media player at
home, like literally the kids have to drop to a console, change directory into the directory,
MPV full screen, the full monthy, but it's classic, even though you know, you have those
dark scenes where everything's moody and you can't see a thing. Like there's a one episode of, uh,
of Star Wars thing that was watching with the, what they, uh, Pucky, and it was so dark,
it was like, there was nothing on, there's literally nothing on the screen, but you could adjust
by hitting three, four, five, six, seven and eight, so you could increase decrease, they brightness,
the sharpness, the gamma level, so at least it was visible what they were doing on the screen.
Brilliant, brilliant player. But, uh, Archer's oven to do a show on bookmarking.
Well, we'll be excellent now, and I exactly are running off on the, they're precious size, my show.
I've never been in a show again. That's, it's an interesting subject. Oh, it's, uh, I've never
gotten, got into MPV. Oh, it's classic, brilliant player. Yeah, I know, I don't miss, Mr. Axe is into
it as well. I've just sort of looked at it and thought, no, not that one, but, um, it's, uh, yeah, it's
quite, uh, quite intriguing to, to use it for something like that. I think I might, well, we'll do that.
Yep, cool. Okay, we'll carry on. What's in my bag, Dave Hingney has a bag, and he's got a
what in it. Patrick says, nice to hear your first show, Dave, I hope, uh, to listen to you again soon, cool.
Yeah, excellent. And I liked that, uh, mustn't your bag, actually, and also I liked the
power bank, that's cool. Yes, yes, yes, no, interesting stuff. Although I don't tend to use
messenger bags myself, but, uh, this looks like a good, if this was a rock sack, I would probably,
I would be interested. Mm-hmm. Yeah, I've used messenger bags in the past, the ones with
laptops, and that sort of stuff, but they're uncomfortable after, for me, anyway, after long
use, whereas a rock sack, you can balance better, you know, even strap it around your waist and
get the, the weight distribution better, I find, but it's a personal matter, it's personal thanks.
It's good. I thought I took the, um, links out of those, uh, in the show, not, I see that they,
they've got all the tracking links still on, but I took all those out. Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
How do they give us? I don't know, that's weird. Okay, I'll have to say another. As a general principle,
we, I think we agreed that we, we should maybe be doing that, um, because, and I was actually
contemplating writing a script to do generic, track, uh, stuff removal, um, and, uh,
these, these being processed. Yeah, I, yeah, I went to the episode and edited it in the database to
remove, because we're kind of weird. Why the back? No, yeah, I don't, I don't know. I, I didn't think
to do it at the time, and you, you, you, you come into it about it afterwards. So, I just left it with you.
So, we're glad to meet the changes for strange, and maybe that Amazon did a restore of the
database. Anyway, some other guy did an introduction to JQ Part One, just informed
about using the JQ utility. And this is what happens, Dave, if you leave a show idea long enough,
somebody else will do it for you and steal all your thunder. There's, there's not a huge amount of
there, actually, a small, or a small paper bag being out being exploded. Um, but yeah, it, yeah,
it's, we've talked about this for ages, as it being needed, but, uh, it was Mr. Axe's show where
he was, um, he was using Python 2 to pass, uh, Jason, which is all fine and good, but if you want
to do anything, um, at the command line, then you really struggle in without this. Um, so I thought,
okay, nice time to, uh, to start on this, down this road. So, there we go. And you've done another
few episodes, and when you've done those, then I can, uh, do other, we'll see, I'm interested to see
where you end, and then, uh, I'm not saying that I'm more of us than you, but I've done some fairly
very popular, you probably are, because you've been using it more than I have, but, uh, that's fine.
I mean, it's brilliant. It's, it's a big subject. It's an enormous subject, and I do not want to
spend the, the next year working on it, particularly. Um, one thing I discovered looking ahead just
the other day is that, uh, Jackie uses a regular expression engine, which I had not heard of before,
um, which is an engine, which tries to consolidate all the others. You know, there's one
used in part, there's one used in Pearl, uh, this one in JavaScript, and it tries to consolidate
them all into one thing, which is, it's a good choice for Jackie, but, uh, you, you've, you've got a,
but you can come in with your, uh, with pretty much all of your, uh, of your regular expression
knowledge, and use it. But if you want to do the more advanced stuff, then you're going to have to
go and do the reading, but how it goes in this, this environment. So, I don't think I should begin
into that aspect of, uh, Jackie, so I think I'll leave that for the reader. Oh, the listener,
to get into more. But yeah, excellent. Um, the following day, my story, how to cure, uh,
thought to cure for my obesity talk about historical wicked and recently I learned, uh, so that,
how to lose weight. And this is the, uh, Jason Feng fasting method, um, and there's one comment.
Is it my turn? Yep. Yeah, trace it. Thank you for sharing. Many of us have struggled with
excess weight. I've been using an intermittent fasting eating pattern quite some time now with mixed
results. And I behave for my remaining meals and minimize my sugars, then all as well.
And I binge any half a box of cookies. It doesn't work so well. So, thanks the inspiration to be
more disciplined. Fantastic. I hope it goes well for, um, your room and maybe a follow up show in a
year. Tell us how it would. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It, uh, I like some of his suggestions about
effectively prolonging your, your nighttime fast, which is what breakfast does. He pointed out. Um,
but by, by not eating, uh, your first meal till later. So that's, that's when I've not heard
up before that. It makes a lot sense. I actually tried the fast diet as the, as the, as the person
was called that I, I, I did for about six months or so a few years ago. It definitely helped
and getting into the habit of just being, being hungry or day, uh, you, you can control it.
And then the meal that you have, this is one where you be fast stored in in it, a meal at night.
The meal that you have at night, which is supposed to be very protonatious and high fiber and
stuff, uh, is, is the most wonderful thing. This is a treat. But you, you don't do it every day. You
know, two days a week or something like that. It helped. But, um, it's a very, very hard thing to do
because you, uh, your body wants to eat stuff because that's the way it's evolved and,
yeah, and designed as it were. So yeah, it's, so yeah, good luck to your own. Um, the following day,
we had my tributes to feed by Henrik, uh, Henrik. Uh, fees are useful and keep me up to the
stages with new information for websites. I am interested in yes, feeds are a thing and they're
absolutely cool. And we have lots of them. One of them, by the way, um, um, um, which brings up
two questions. On MasterDone, on the HDR channel, we have a lot of engagements with community.
And one of the comments that a single past was that somebody requesting not necessarily for HDR,
for another, you know, to general call to all bugcasters out there,
please include the transcripts as a feed. And we, of course, have transcripts here on HDR.
So we should be producing a RSS feed with the transcripts. It would be trivial, no, no problem.
They're whatsoever. Uh, the only thing is which version should we use community impulse,
please advise, please advise over. Um, so that was that? Uh, great, great job. Yeah, I would also like
to know how to get the feed out of MasterDone, up for mentions about HDR because I think we should
include some of those comments here on the community news. So if you, if anybody has any
knows how to do that, so that I don't have to do it, can you please tell us that would be great.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I did manage to get no notifications coming out in a feed in Thunderbird,
but they're not very reliable. So in certain notifications I get. So yeah, I'd like to know
that as well. There's bits of MasterDone, which are still quite strange, I find.
Um, I've no idea what this, uh, anyway, I said, hold some, I might, somebody do an introduction
day to MasterDone first, that'd be great. Yes. Then the next day, which was, I think the last day,
is a correct day. It is, yep, uh, response to HDR 40 65, a shout out to a shout out about the
framework laptop by Swift 110. And this is more stuff about the, um, new news was talking about
the initial, um, about the framework laptop and stuff. So this was a response to that. Those
framework laptops look really cool and upgraded and awesome. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
time to drooling about, if I didn't have enough computers. Yeah, yeah, it's, uh, same here,
anyway, uh, I'm more desktop-y these days rather than laptop-y. But, uh, yeah, if I wasn't the
Microsoft laptop, that would be one of which would be very keen on. So that was this. What else was
in the dark at Dave? So we have a couple of comments from previous shows. Um, I'll start with
a news show by some guy on the internet. And we get the comment number two on that from El
Muscle about George Santos. Uh, that was, uh, I was mentioned on that particular episode. An excellent
podcast on Santos from a left queer perspective explicit in brackets. Bad guys, George Santos.
episode web page and he gives a link to bad gay is pod. A pod being.com and media file.
Also a pod being link on that subject. Yeah. And there was a comment on the
Norst making a pung. Dury timer and operator does some free free.
Dark nose diagnosis. Thank you. You got Aded Abro and the picture to the autism spectrum disorder.
A page. Hello, I don't think it's just one. Yeah, it's like, I got, I mean, I understood
why he was coming from. And yeah, it's, once you become alerted to these things, then you, uh,
you see it everywhere. Just true. Um, in the, or skipping over the events calendar, there's a link
there in the short, so it'll probably be moving to the main page. Um, in other business, Craig
Meloni host of the open metal cast has passed away. And, um, we're putting together a little bit
of, um, remembrance for him. Um, we're going to do that this month, uh, possibly playing one of
the episodes. Um, so if there's anything, if, uh, he was a, it was unbelievable. The number of
communities that he was involved in, um, uh, like carrots and pepper and carrots, uh, a lot of,
he was, uh, one of the co-op maintainers over there. He was involved in Linux user groups and
the link there to his victory, uh, Greg Guy will be sorely missed by the community. And, um, so if
you have anything in any way affected your life and you want to contribute anything to this, uh,
episode, um, feel free to do so either text and I'll read it out or if you have some audio,
you can send it in to me. That's regretting. Or would you do? Yes, but I just put an item in about
one of the, uh, issues that was raised on get you a repository, which was, uh, to do with, uh,
using mutton for show notes and, um, the issue was that if you're using, if you use syntax
highlighting for fenced code blocks, that's where you, you wrote a bit of script or whatever,
whatever code you're writing, you put three backticks before and after it, but the first set of
backticks followed by the, the name of the language and you expect in certain contexts for,
um, script for the, um, highlighting to be enabled. So you get different colors for the,
various elements of the language, but this doesn't work for us and the reason for that
is that, um, well, I've turned it off because the way it's implemented, uh, using Pandok
is that it adds a lot of div and span tags around bits of, of text that, uh, to be highlighted.
And when that became available and we tried sending it to, uh, after all, then we found that
all of the tags were stripped out. Um, so you lost, you lost any highlighting that, uh,
that you might have wanted added. Um, so what I've said is that I will look to see if I can, uh,
um, uh, whether that restrictions were lifted, whether that, the stripping out has finished,
or not. And the other thought is, well, put the, uh, the, um, the complex, the colored stuff in the notes
on the HBR site and the static site. Yeah. And if it gets stripped out on on our code,
oh, well, so be it. Um, we'll, we'll not, we'll not show any tears on it. So, uh, just,
making the point that, uh, I'm going to try and look at that over the next month and see what's
the best way through. I'm on a question. We've done the migration of the websites, uh, and stuff.
So we have content that's in the database. So we've got the HBR, uh,
hub, which has got their PHP stuff that can really only be done in one place.
Then we've got the automatic generating stuff, which looks at the database and then generates all
the static files. But aside from that, there are general static files that don't, but are not part
of the database that we need to keep, for example, host images and, um, um,
one files of the host introducing themselves. Hello, my name is Ken. For example, those are
outside of that as are the show notes. As are they, and not the show notes, but as are they, um,
extended show notes when that's the case. images or attachments or source code and stuff like that.
So it was always my intention to have an RSS, you know, transparency. If you transparency layer,
so if you imagine it as you have a blank disk and then you or think of all the static stuff,
and then you have on top of that, you superimpose the dynamically generated stuff from the
database. It should, with both of those things, you should be able to get everything. And one of the
other transparencies is the media files, which will be a choice, whether you download those or not,
from the internet archive, or locally. So I'm, so that's work that's ongoing, and I
have them to document that as yes. I know Ken, I know I've been bugging you a lot of rage.
We have, this is a subject which is past, past, but past is by, we have told one another
about it and told ourselves about it, probably as well, but it's not necessarily moved
forward significantly. Yeah, so I absolutely agree. And we, we, we do need to reach some
decisions about how we deal with it. And the reason the reason I bring it up now is that I'm in
the process of cheering out. So I'm trying to get that second computer at home sort of, but every time
I do, I run into other issues. And I've got a large turbine size disk drive that can associate with
that. And now we're bandwidth. I have half a gig of upload that I can dedicate to serving HPR files,
which will be more than enough, I reckon. So the infrastructure is being worked on in order to be
able to do that and the implementation itself is, is some arson script switch, shouldn't be too
bad. But if somebody has a way of advising us on how to track media outside of gas. So I don't know
where we use art factory as a method of doing that. But what is the other way of tracking stuff,
tracking files, and check some files. We're doing that manually in the database.
And we're also doing a little bit in git, but I don't want all the images and web files being
in git. And equally, it's a pain having them in the database, having to manage that in the database,
is there a like tool that I can go up gas and stall, blah, and point to that something and go
here. This is managed this for me. There is a tool I just wrote for you and Pearl.
No, no, I haven't a bad day, I've not written it yet. There is something called git and net
annex, which I've heard people using for that type of thing where you've got a lot of
non-gitable inappropriate for git type files, but you want to track them all through through
git, git annexes. And I think there's a number of others that are similar to it.
I don't have any direct experience of just heard people talking about them. So yeah,
hopefully we'll find that or be pointed in that sort of direction, but anybody who knows about them.
Yep, so it's written in her skull. God, I thought it was only somebody who knew her scalpy
or could talk to us about that. Apparently, JQ is originally written in her skull, so yeah,
that was not written in C, but yeah, cool, cool. So I think that's it, Dave.
I think it is, yes, yes, that's everything. Thanks again for adjusting the time to do this.
Problem. Tune in tomorrow for another exciting episode of Hacker.
Public.
Radio.
You have been listening to Hacker Public Radio at Hacker Public Radio.org.
Today's show was contributed by a HDR listener like yourself. If you ever thought of
recording podcast, click on our contributally to find out how easy it means.
Hosting for HDR has been kindly provided by an onsthost.com,
the internet archive and our synced.net. On the satellite stages,
today's show is released on our creative comments,
attribution for.0.0 international license.